Jano González

Berlin, Germany | info@janogonzalez.com | github.com/janogonzalez

Profile

Software Engineer with 15+ years experience designing, implementing and operating highly available distributed systems that serve millions of requests per minute with millisecond latency.

Has led teams of up to 7 people, mentored 10+ engineers and presented in conferences like <u>LISA</u>, <u>RubyNation</u> and <u>JRubyConf</u>.

Experience

Staff Software Engineer – Spotify

Staff Software Engineer – Shopify

2023 – Present
2021 – 2022

Staff Software Engineer - Contentful

- 2020 2021
- Ensured a safe rollout of the GraphQL Content API to tens of thousands of customers by introducing a new tenant type with its own infrastructure and rate limits
- Decreased toil by introducing self-service AWS permission configuration for teams

Senior Software Engineer – SoundCloud

2014 - 2020

- Secured 6 extra years without space issues in the main database cluster by extracting social graph microservices out of the main Ruby on Rails monolith
- Designed and implemented microservices using Scala and JRuby, coordinated the integration with 5+ engineering teams and safely rolled out traffic to millions of users
- Improved resource utilization by 50% and enabled multiple deploys per day by migrating the main Ruby on Rails monolith from bare-metal to Kubernetes
- Identified lack of new contributors to the main Ruby on Rails monolith as a risk. Mitigated the risk by introducing an ownership plan and aligning 5+ engineering teams around it
- Mentored 7 developers including colleagues and interns from the Rails Girls SoC program

CTO – Hop.In 2012 – 2013

• Recruited and led a team of 5 developers to drive the transition from prototype to MVP

Senior Software Engineer – Continuum

2011
Engineering Manager / Project Manager – Taisa

2008 – 2010
Software Engineer – Depósito Central de Valores

2005 – 2008
Software Engineer – Everis

Education

Software Engineer – Universidad del Bío-Bío, Chile

2000 - 2004

Technical Skills

- Languages: Ruby, Scala, Go, JavaScript, SQL, Java
- **Technologies:** MySQL, Kafka, Cassandra, Kubernetes, AWS, GCP, Prometheus, Terraform
- Other: Distributed Systems, Site Reliability Engineering, Test Driven Development